# **Matthew Farquharson**

**UX/UI** Designer

763-607-7210 | matthewfarquharson@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a product designer with an emphasis on user research and information architecture. As a user centered designer, I think that by studying and observing cognitive and behavioral patterns, one can design an experience with the ability to influence human behavior. If you're interested in working with someone who values the importance of designing user centered products while improving the ROI of the business, please reach out. I'd love to talk with you.

### **PROJECTS**

Kudu | View Demo | March 2020

Lead UX / UI Designer

Kudu empowers digital content creators to manage, share, and track their assets.

Designed for both desktop and mobile devices, it is essentially a social media management platform with standard drive features. Users can post their content to all of their various social media accounts and use basic analytics to track their post activity.

BusyBus | View Demo | December 2019

Lead UX / UI Designer

BusyBus is a simple mobile transit that allows users to track when certain buses are arriving at specific bus stops.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Thinkful Apprenticeship | Product Design Flex | October 2019 – Present

- Learned industry best practices and design process standards with a focus on UX research, visual design, and front-end development
- Created and deployed projects while learning new tools and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a lead product designer at Amazon.

## Quinn Violins & Fret Central | Sales Representative | May 2018 - March 2020

- · Created online product listings on Amazon and Reverb, and to assist all customers.
- By becoming familiar with common customer questions, I made it my goal to design informative product listings that enabled customers to make the purchases without assistance.
- By doing this, the music shop noticed an increase in online sales, further validating my desire to explore a career in UX.

EDUCATION	SKILLS	
University of Colorado, Boulder	User surveys	Personas
Bachelor of Music, Violin Performance	Wireframing	User flows
GPA: 3.6   2013 – 2018	<b>Usability testing</b>	HTML/CSS
	Journey mapping	JavaScript
	Competitive analysis	